Meet Two Unlikely Heroes With A Bone To Pick.
102 Dalmatians is a family, comedy film directed by Kevin Lima.
Get ready for a howling good time as an all new assortment of
irresistible animal heroes are unleashed in this great family tail!
In an unlikely alliance, the outrageous Waddlesworth - a parrot who thinks he's a Rottweiler -
teams up with Oddball - an un-marked Dalmatian puppy eager to earn her spots!
Together they embark on a laugh-packed quest to
outwit the ever-scheming Cruella De Vil.
Cruella de Vil, played by Glenn Close.
Jean Pierre Le Pelt, played by Gérard Depardieu.
Kevin Shepherd, played by Ioan Gruffudd.
Chloe Simon, played by Alice Evans.
Alonzo, played by Tim McInnerny.
Waddlesworth (voice), played by Eric Idle.
102 Dalmatians is a 2000 American crime comedy film produced by Walt Disney
Pictures and distributed  by Buena Vista Pictures Distribution.
Directed by Kevin Lima from a screenplay by Kristen Buckley, Brian Regan, Bob Tzudiker and Noni White, and based on a story by Buckley and
Regan, it is the sequel to 101 Dalmatians (1996), which was a live-action remake of the 1961 animated film of the same name.
It stars Glenn Close reprising her role as Cruella de Vil as she attempts to steal puppies for her "grandest" fur coat yet, with Ioan Gruffudd, Alice Evans, Tim McInnerny, Ian
Richardson, Gérard Depardieu, Ben Crompton, Carol MacReady, Jim Carter, Ron Cook, David Horovitch, Timothy West, and the voice of Eric Idle in supporting roles.
Close and McInnerny were the only two actors from the 1996 film to return for the sequel, while Adrian Biddle
and Anthony Powell reprised their respective duties as cinematographer and costume designer.
The film received negative reviews from critics, and grossed a total of
$183.6 million worldwide against a budget of $85 million.
It was nominated for the Academy Award for Best Costume Design.
A backstory film in its own continuity, Cruella, was released on May 28, 2021, with
Emma Stone in the title role and Close acting as an executive producer.
The film explores themes of prison, london, england,
release from prison, parrot, women's prison.
The tone is lighthearted.